Kidochukwu B. Anyasi

Lagos, Nigeria | +234 816 995 8688 | anyasibright@gmail.com https://github.com/justmisty | https://www.linkedin.com/in/brightanyasi/

Summary

A seasoned frontend developer with 3 years of expertise in Node.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Firebase, and other technologies. Collaborated closely with a small team to build and launch functional and responsive web applications, contributed to code reviews, bug fixes, and continuous improvement of the codebase. Demonstrated a strong commitment to learning and growth, actively seeking out new challenges. I believe in writing clean code that is not only functional but also maintainable and elegant. My attention to detail extends to consistent indentation, meaningful variable names, and well-organized project structures.

Hard Skills

- JavaScript
- NodeJS
- Mongo Db
- HTML5
- CSS3
- ReactJS

- NextJs
- TypeScript
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind CSS
- Firebase
- Wordpress
- Version Control (Git)
- Algorithm and Data Structure
- Software Development
- Life Cycle (SLDC)
- Performance Optimization
- Testing and Debugging

- API integration
- Framer Motion
- Security

Soft Skills

- Team Work
- Leadership
- Presentation
- Problem Solving
- Adaptability
- Attention to detail
- Customer Onboarding
- Effective Communication
- Time Management

Experience

SOAIR Technologies Africa, Lagos, Nigeria (Frontend Developer)

11/2022 - Present

 Led a team of developers on a web development project lifecycle from planning to implementation that is 100% user-friendly with over 200 monthly users. Utilizing HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Firebase and Mongo-Db.

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including UI/UX designers and project managers, to build seamless, 100% user experiences, implemented features including user management and authentication.
- Ensured 100% data integrity and security, with a 30% boost in database security. Used Git to manage and track code changes.

Ensure Services, Lagos, Nigeria (Computer Service Engineer- Intern)

05/2021 - 06/2022

- Engaged in rigorous testing routines to verify the reliability and performance of computer hardware.
- Identified and resolved several root causes of hardware and software malfunctions.
- Regularly carried out maintenance tasks crucial for optimal performance.
- Provided technical support to customers and employees, offering guidance on system setup, configuration, and maintenance which resulted in significant productivity boost

Nigerdock Nigeria Limited, Lagos, Nigeria (IT Support Engineer- SIWES)

07/2018 - 01/2019

- Installed well-functional LAN and managed IP, servers and other network components
- Assessed performance of operating systems, software and hardware, and also addressed any other problems observed.
- Troubleshoot system failures or errors and provided solutions to restore functionality.
- Trained junior interns in rapid troubleshooting, resulting in increments in service uptime.

Education

Olusegun Agagu University of Science and Tech.

Bachelor of Technology
(B. Tech) – Computer Science
2022

Matrix Computer Institute

 Diploma in Desktop Publishing 2015

Language

English - Proficient